Guide to the Sheffield Scientific School, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Trustees and Governing Board Records, 1871-1967; Series I
  - Records of the Board of Trustees Meetings
    - Agenda, auditor ' s report, financial statements, minutes, treasurer's report, 1953 October 29 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Agenda, auditor's report, financial statements, securities list, 1954 October 21 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Agenda, auditor's report, financial statements, securities list, treasurer's report, 1955 October 24 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Minutes, 1963 October 30 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, financial statements, reports, 1964 October 20 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, financial statements, minutes, reports, 1965 October 28 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Financial statements, minutes, reports, 1967 February 14 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Agenda, correspondence, financial statements, minutes, reports, 1967 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Financial Records
    - Clark (Noyes D.) Estate, 1937-1945 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Clark (Dwight N. and Noyes D.) Fund, 1938-1950 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Class of 1879, Brush Fund, 1904-1905, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Class of 1887 Fund, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - General: copies of agreements and historical papers re: bequests and funds, 1871, 1901, 1914, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Havemeyer (Julia and Loomis) Bequest, 1939, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Henderson (John Phillips) Estate, 1939-1945, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 41 - 43)
    - Hotchkiss (Marie Oakes) Estate, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Hotchkiss (Marie Oakes) Estate: correspondence re: upkeep and sale, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Hotchkiss (Marie Oakes) Estate: legal business, 1938-1939, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Hotchkiss (Marie Oakes) Fund, 1913-1915, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Stone Trust Corporation Scholarship Prize Fund, 1911, 1920, 1931, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Terry (Edward Clinton and James) Fund, 1946-1947, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Tighe, Lawrence G., Treasurer: correspondence re: Sheffield Scientific School funds, 1943-1945 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Vanderbilt (Frederick W.) Estate and Will: correspondence and financial papers, 1938-1945 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Vanderbilt, Frederick We: pre-estate: correspondence and copies of legal documents re: gifts and funds, 1928-1930, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Whittlesey (C.W.). Fund: correspondence, 1904, 193-1940 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Minutes of the Governing Board Meetings
    - 1872 Sep 30 - 1873 Jun 9 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - 1873 Nov 10 - 1898 Jun 20 (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - 1898 Oct 3 - 1908 Jun 1 7 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - 1908 Oct 5 - 1917 Jun 13 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - 1917 Sep 26 - 1926 Jun 7 (Box 7, Folder 58 - 59)
    - 1926 Oct 14 - 1956 May 21 (Box 8, Folder 60)
- Faculty Minutes, circa 1852-1945; Series II
  Series II, FACULTY MINUTES, 1860-1945, documents the Sheffield Scientific School's day-to-day academic and student related activities. The minutes contain, among other things, information on curriculum, catalogue descriptions, teaching schedules, examination results, minutes of the class instructors meetings, action taken with students'in academic trouble and student discipline.
  The Sheffield Scientific School faculty was originally called the Board of Instructors. Beginning on October 24, 1932, the Sheffield Scientific School faculty met jointly with the School of Engineering faculty. It should be noted that these minutes are not complete to 1956 and that gaps exist in the time span represented.
  The materials in Series II are arranged chronologically.
  - List of candidates for the Bachelor of Philosophy degree as recommended by the instructors, 1852 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Minutes of the Faculty Meetings (bound volumes)
    - 1860 September 20 - 1866 September 13 (Box 9, Folder 62-63)
    - 1866 September 19 - 1872 April 24 (Box 9, Folder 64-65)
    - 1872 April 27 - 1885 June 18 (Box 9, Folder 66-67)
    - Freshman class report of examinations, 1885 June (Box 9, Folder 68)
    - Junior and senior class report of examinations, 1885 June (Box 9, Folder 69)
    - 1885 June 19 - 1891 March 19 (Box 9, Folder 70-71)
    - 1889 October 2 - 1903 January 17 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    - 1903 September 23 - 1905 December 11 (Box 10, Folder 73)
    - 1905 September 27 - 1914 June 10 (Box 11, Folder 74-75)
    - (1932 Oct 24 - 1937 Jun 18, joint meeting of the Sheffield Scientific School and the School of Engineering faculty), 1914 October 5 - 1937 June 18 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - (joint meetings of the Sheffield Scientific School and the School of Engineering faculty), 1937 November 29 - 1945 February 22 (Box 12, Folder 77-78)
- Administrative Records, 1864-1956; Series III
  Series III, ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS, is divided into ten sections:
  Russell Henry Chittenden, 1909-1922
  Charles Hyde Warren and Edmund W. Sinnott, 1922-1956
  Annual Reports, 1925-1945
  Committee on the Selection of a Successor to Sheffield Scientific School Director Russell H. Chittenden, 1921-1922
  Appointing Board Records, 1864-1894
  Semi-centennial Celebration, 1897
  Centennial Celebration, 1947
  Student Register, 1861-1864
  Official Notices, 1860s-1940s
  Materials include correspondence, policy statements, Yale University reorganization material, early admissions material, personnel records, several histories of the Sheffield Scientific School, and information regarding the effects of the two world wars on the Sheffield Scientific School. There is no material from the George Jarvis Brush administration (1872-1898).
  The Sheffield Scientific School served as the land grant agricultural college for Connecticut from 1863-1893. The primary function of the Appointing Board and the State Board of Visitors was to fill vacancies in state scholarships to the Sheffield Scientific School. The minutes of the Appointing Board meetings record routine business and procedures as well as choice of scholars and awarded funds. Official Notices consists of forms and notices issued from the Directors and/or Registrar's Offices from 1860s- 1940s. Materials include announcements, exam schedules, meal forms, notices of school closings, and commencement activities.
  Director Russell H. chittendents correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject of the correspondence. Note: for a list of Russell Henry Chittenden selected correspondents see Appendix I. These papers contain one major subsection - World War I Activities - organized alphabetically by subject. The papers of Directors Charles Hyde Warren and Edmund W. Sinnott are combined in one file arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject. These papers contain one major subgroup - Personnel Records - arranged alphabetically by person or department.
  The Annual Reports are arranged chronologically. Committee on the Sefection of a Successor to Sheffield Scientific School Director Russell H. Chittenden, Appointing Board Records and Semi-Centennial Celebration Records are organized by form. Centennial Celebration Records are organized alphabetically with one major subsection - the Committee on Arrangements. The Student Register and Official Notices are arranged chronologically.
  - Russell Henry Chittenden, 1909-1922
    - General Correspondence, 1909-1922
      - Abb-Abr, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 79)
      - Ada-Ado, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 80)
      - Agu-Ake, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 81)
      - Ald-Ale, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 82)
      - All-Alv, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 83)
      - Amb -Ams, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 84)
      - Ana-Ans, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 85)
      - App, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 86)
      - Arc-Arn, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 87)
      - Ash-Asl, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 88)
      - Ath-Att, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 89)
      - Aub -Aus, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 90)
      - Ave-Ayr, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 91)
      - Bab-Bag, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 92)
      - Bai, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 93)
      - Bak, 1909-1922 (Box 13, Folder 94)
      - Bal-Ban, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 95)
      - Bara-Barn, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 96)
      - Barr-Bart, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 97)
      - Bas-Bat, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 98)
      - Bau-Bay, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 99)
      - Bea-Bec, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 100)
      - Bee-Bel, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 101)
      - Ben, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 102)
      - Ber-Bez, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 103)
      - Bic-Bin, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 104)
      - Bis, 1909-1922 (Box 14, Folder 105)
      - Bla-Blu, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 106)
      - Boa-Bou, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 107)
      - Bow-Boz, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 108)
      - Bra, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 109)
      - Breckenridge, Lester Paige, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 110 - 111)
      - Breh-Brew, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 112)
      - Bri, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 113)
      - Bro-Broo, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 114)
      - Brow, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 115)
      - Bru-Bry, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 116)
      - Bue-Bul, 1909-1922 (Box 15, Folder 117)
      - Bum-Burn, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 118)
      - Burr-But, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 119)
      - Bye-Byr, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 120)
      - Cae-Cal, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 121)
      - Cam-Cap, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 122)
      - Car-Cat, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 123)
      - Ced-Cem, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 124)
      - Cha, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 125)
      - Che-Chi, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 126)
      - Chr- Chu, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 127)
      - Cia, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 128)
      - Clap-Clar, 1909-1922 (Box 16, Folder 129)
      - Clax-Clo, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 130)
      - Coa-Cof, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 131)
      - Cog-Com, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 132)
      - Con, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 133)
      - Coo, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - Cop-Cos, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 135)
      - Cot-Cou, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 136)
      - Cra-Cro, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 137)
      - Cul-Cut, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 138)
      - Dah-Dar, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 139)
      - Dau-Day, 1909-1922 (Box 17, Folder 140)
      - Dea-Def, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 141)
      - de: Forest, Lee, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 142)
      - Dei-Dew, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 143)
      - Dib-Dix, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 144)
      - Dod-Doy, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 145)
      - Dra-Dru, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 146)
      - Dub-Dzi, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 147)
      - Ear-Eis, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 148)
      - Ekb-Ely, 1909-1922 (Box 18, Folder 149)
      - Eme-Ete, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 150)
      - Eva-Eyr, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 151)
      - Far-Fer, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 152)
      - Fie-Fish, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 153)
      - Fisk-Fly, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 154)
      - Fog-Foy, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 155)
      - Fra, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 156)
      - Fre-Ful, 1909-1922 (Box 19, Folder 157)
      - Gad-Gay, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 158)
      - Ged-Gen, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 159)
      - Geology Summer School, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 160)
      - Geor-Gey, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 161)
      - Gib-Gig, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 162)
      - Gil-Giv, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 163)
      - Gle-Glo, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 164)
      - God-Goo, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 165)
      - Gor-Gow, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 166)
      - Gra, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 167)
      - Gre, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 168)
      - Gri-Gut, 1909-1922 (Box 20, Folder 169)
      - Hab-Hal, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 170)
      - Ham-Han, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 171)
      - Hard-Harr, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 172)
      - Hart-Hartwell, Arthur, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 173)
      - Hartwell, John Augustus, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 174)
      - Harv-Harw, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 175)
      - Has-Hat, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 176)
      - Hau-Haz, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 177)
      - Hea-Hei, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 178)
      - Hel-Hen, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 179)
      - Her-Hey, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 180)
      - Hib-Hin, 1909-1922 (Box 21, Folder 181)
      - Hoa-Hol, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 182)
      - Horn-Hot, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 183)
      - Hou-Hoy, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 184)
      - Hua-Hum, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 185)
      - Hun-Hym, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 186)
      - Idd-Iri, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 187)
      - Irving, Anna Duer, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 188)
      - Irving, John Duer, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 189)
      - Irw-Ive, 1909-1922 (Box 22, Folder 190)
      - Jac-Jak, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 191)
      - Jam, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 192)
      - Jan-Jar, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 193)
      - Jeb-Jey, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 194)
      - Johns, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 195)
      - Johnson, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 196)
      - Johnston-Jon, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 197)
      - Jor-Jun, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 198)
      - Kad-Kay, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 199)
      - Kea-Kellogg, 1909-1922 (Box 23, Folder 200)
      - Kelly-Kha, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 201)
      - Kib-Kin, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 202)
      - Kir-Kiw, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 203)
      - Kle-Kli, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 204)
      - Kna-Kor, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 205)
      - Kos-Kyl, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 206)
      - Laa-Lam, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 207)
      - Lan-Lar, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 208)
      - Las-Laz, 1909-1922 (Box 24, Folder 209)
      - Lea-Lee, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 210)
      - Lef -Ley, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 211)
      - Lib-Lin, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 212)
      - Lip-Llo, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 213)
      - Loc-Lon, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 214)
      - Loo-Low, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 215)
      - Luc-Lut, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 216)
      - Lyf -Lys, 1909-1922 (Box 25, Folder 217)
      - Mab, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 218)
      - MacA-MacCle, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 219)
      - MacCli-MacCul, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 220)
      - MacD-MacI, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 221)
      - MacK-MacM, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 222)
      - MacN-Macy, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 223)
      - Mad-Man, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 224)
      - Mar, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 225)
      - Mat, 1909-1922 (Box 26, Folder 226)
      - Mau-May, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 227)
      - Mea-Mei, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 228)
      - Mel-Men, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 229)
      - Mer-Mey, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 230)
      - Mic-Milk, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 231)
      - Miller, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 232)
      - Milli-Mix, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 233)
      - Moa-Moo, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 234)
      - Mora-Morg, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 235)
      - Mori-Mos, 1909-1922 (Box 27, Folder 236)
      - Motor Vehicles, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 237)
      - Mott-Moy, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 238)
      - Muc-Mye, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 239)
      - Nab-Nay, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 240)
      - Nea-Nev, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 241)
      - New, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 242)
      - Nic, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 243)
      - Nis-Nix, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 244)
      - Nob-Nye, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 245)
      - Oak-Oli, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 246)
      - Olm-Osb, 1909-1922 (Box 28, Folder 247)
      - Osler, Sir William, 1899-1912, 1920 (Box 29, Folder 248)
      - Ost-Owe, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 249)
      - Owyang, Earl C., 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 250)
      - Oxl, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 251)
      - Pac-Page, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 252)
      - Page Lectures, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 253)
      - Pagt-Pard, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 254)
      - Park-Pay, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 255)
      - Pea-Pei, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 256)
      - Pen-Per, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 257)
      - Pet-Pew, 1909-1922 (Box 29, Folder 258)
      - Pfa-Phy, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 259)
      - Pic-Pira, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 260)
      - Pirsson, Louis V., 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 261)
      - Pirt-Pos, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 262)
      - Pot-Poy, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 263)
      - Pra, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 264)
      - Pre-Pry, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 265)
      - Pub-Pye, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 266)
      - Qui, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 267)
      - Rag-Rap, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 268)
      - Rat-Ray, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 269)
      - Rea-Rem, 1909-1922 (Box 30, Folder 270)
      - Ren-Rey, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 271)
      - Rhe-Ric, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 272)
      - Rid-Rit, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 273)
      - Roa-Rob, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 274)
      - Roc-Rog, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 275)
      - Rom-Ror, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 276)
      - Ros-Rot, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 277)
      - Rou-Ryd, 1909-1922 (Box 31, Folder 278)
      - Saa-San, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 279)
      - Sar-Sax, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 280)
      - Sca-Schel, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 281)
      - Schem-Schoe, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 282)
      - Scholarships, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 283)
      - Schole-Schew, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 284)
      - Scob-Scot, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 285)
      - Scov-Scu, 1909-1922 (Box 32, Folder 286)
      - Sea-Sel, 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 287)
      - Ser-Sey, 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 288)
      - Sha-Shef, 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 289)
      - Shel-Sher, 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 290)
      - Shi-Sjo, 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 291)
      - Ske-Sid, 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 292)
      - Sma-Smith, J., 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 293)
      - Smith, K.-Smo, 1909-1922 (Box 33, Folder 294)
      - Sna-Sny, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 295)
      - Soc-Sou, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 296)
      - Spa-Stal, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 297)
      - Standard Oil Company, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 298)
      - Stanl-Stec, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 299)
      - Sted-Stet, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 300)
      - Stev-Stey, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 301)
      - Sti-Strak, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 302)
      - Strathcona Scholarship, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 303)
      - Stratt-Sty, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 304)
      - Suc-Sut, 1909-1922 (Box 34, Folder 305)
      - Swain, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 306)
      - Swan-Syk, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 307)
      - Taf-Tau, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 308)
      - Taylor, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 309)
      - Tea-Thi, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 310)
      - Thomas, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 311)
      - Thompson, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 312)
      - Thorn, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 313)
      - Til-Tit, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 314)
      - Tob-Tow, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 315)
      - Tra, 1909-1922 (Box 35, Folder 316)
      - Tre-Tru, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 317)
      - Tsa-Tyn, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 318)
      - Ude-Unt, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 319)
      - Van-Ver, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 320)
      - Via-Vre, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 321)
      - Wad-Walk, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 322)
      - Wall-Ward, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 323)
      - Warf -Warr, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 324)
      - Was-Wat, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 325)
      - Wea-Weis, 1909-1922 (Box 36, Folder 326)
      - Weit-Wel, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 327)
      - Wen-Wey, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 328)
      - Whe-White, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 329)
      - Whiti-Whitt, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 330)
      - Wic-Wille, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 331)
      - Williams, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 332)
      - Williamson-Wils, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 333)
      - Wim-Win, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 334)
      - Wis-Wood, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 335)
      - Woodc-Wor, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 336)
      - Wra-Wym, 1909-1922 (Box 37, Folder 337)
      - Yale, 1909-1922 (Box 38, Folder 338)
      - Yam-Yun, 1909-1922 (Box 38, Folder 339)
      - Zab-Zim, 1909-1922 (Box 38, Folder 340)
    - World War I Activities, 1914-1922
      - Aeronautics, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 341)
      - Agriculture, Department of: correspondence re: Forest Service, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 342)
      - American Council on Education, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 343)
      - Beard, Colonel L.A.: correspondence re: loan of army blankets to Sheffield Scientific School, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 344)
      - Bureau of Mines, Department of the Interior, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 345)
      - Civil Service Commission, United States, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 346)
      - Correspondence and general administrative material, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 347 - 348)
      - Engineer Enlisted Reserve Corps, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 349 - 350)
      - Engineer Enlisted Reserve Corps: correspondence re: summer work for technical students, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 351)
      - Engineer Officers' Training Camp, Camp Lee, Petersburg, Virginia, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 352)
      - Federal Board for Vocational Education, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 353 - 354)
      - Hoyle, Captain R.E.D.: correspondence re: use of army equipment at Sheffield Scientific School Engineering Camp, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 355)
      - Labor, Department of, 1914-1922 (Box 39, Folder 356)
      - Medical Enlisted Reserve Corps, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 357)
      - Military certificates: correspondence, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 358)
      - Motor Transport Corps: correspondence with Colonel J.A. Corcoran, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 359)
      - National Research Council: correspondence from R. A. Millikan, Vice-Chairman, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 360)
      - National Reserve Force, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 361)
      - Naval Training Unit, Yale, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 362)
      - Railroad Wage Commission, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 363)
      - Reserve Officers Training Corps, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 364 - 365)
      - Signal Corps, Radio Division, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 366)
      - Student Army Training Corps, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 367 - 368)
      - Students in all fields of military and naval services: list, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 369)
      - War Department, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 370)
      - War Department, Office of the Chief of Ordinance, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 371)
      - War Industries Board, Council of National Defense, 1914-1922 (Box 40, Folder 372)
        General
        See also: Series IV, box 65, folders 707-708 (U.S. government contracts for rental of Sheffield Scientific School buildings during World War I)
  - Charles Hyde Warren and Edmund W. Sinnott
    - Correspondence, 1922-1956
      - Abbott, Wilbur Cortez: gradebook, 1919-1920 (Box 41, Folder 373)
      - Alejandrino Scholarship, General Jose for a Filipino student to do graduate, work in the sciences or engineering at Yale, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 374)
      - American Association for the Advancement of Science, F.R. Moulton,-Permanent Secretary: correspondence re: moving the American Association for the Advancement of Science offices to New Haven, 1941-1942, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 375)
      - Angell, James R., President of Yale University: correspondence, 1930-1935 (Box 41, Folder 376)
      - Architect, Yale University Supervising See: folder 401, Frank Miles Day
      - Architectural Plans, Committee on, 1927-1928 (Box 41, Folder 377)
      - Army Specialized Training Program, 1943-1944 (Box 41, Folder 378)
      - Athletic Association, 1943-1945 (Box 41, Folder 379)
      - Belknap Prizes, 1911-1912 (Box 41, Folder 380)
      - Biological sciences: general information, 1922-1937 (Box 41, Folder 381)
      - Biological Sciences, Division of: departmental program 1-9, 1944-1945 (Box 41, Folder 382 - 383)
      - Biological Sciences, President's Committee on the, 1938-1940 (Box 41, Folder 384)